A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing, 1972-2015
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing, 1972-2015
The Library of Virginia
34785, 41647, 41666, 43273, 52778
25 cubic feet (25 Boxes)
Virginia Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted documents have been flagged within the collection.
Acquisition Information
Accession 34785 was transferred 27 December 1994.
Accession 41647 was transferred 6 January 2005.
Accession 43273 was transferred 13 June 2007.
Accession 52778 was transferred 28 June 2019.
Historical Information
The Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing was established as a state agency under the Secretary of Human Resources by the 1972 General Assembly. Its predecessor was the Council on the Deaf. The Dept. is advised by a nine member board (Advisory Board to the Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing) appointed by the governor. Four members of the board should be representatives of deaf-oriented professions, four should be hearing-impaired citizens and one member should be a parent of a hearing-impaired child. The board is responsible for the approval of long-range programs and reviews budget requests.
The governor also appoints a director for the agency who is responsible for developing a program for statewide interpreter services for the hearing-impaired, providing training and technical assistance to service providers and the general public about hearing impairment, acting as an advocate for the deaf and hard of hearing, providing communications accessibility for hearing-impaired citizens through its Telecommunications Assistance Program, providing local and statewide outreach services and maintaining a register of hearing-impaired Virginians. This register is confidential and is used for needs assessment and research purposes. The Code of Virginia (63.1-85.1.1 et seq.) establishes the department as a communications bridge between those who are deaf or hard of hearing and hearing persons.
Scope and Content
Records of the Virginia Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing, 1972-2015, are housed in 25 boxes and are arranged in original order. These records consist of Director's correspondence, administrative files, and subject files and includes correspondence, financial documentation, meeting records, policies and procedures, press releases, project documentation, reports, speeches and topical files. Contains the files of several Directors, Acting Directors and Deputy Directors, including Ronald Lanier, J. Rex Purvis, F.P. Yates, Lily P. Bess, Wayne Shoot, Kathy Vesley, William Hill, Clayton Bowen and Susan Buckland.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Director's correspondence and subject files, 1972-1987 (Accession 34785)
Director's correspondence and subject files, 1974-2001 (Accession 41647)
Director's correspondence and subject files, 1974-1996 (Accession 43273)
Director's correspondence and subject files, 1973-2015 (Accession 52778)
Contents List
- Director's correspondence and subject files (Accession 34785), 1972-1987., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 1-9)
  This series is housed in 9 boxes and is arranged in original order. These files include correspondence, financial documentation, meeting files, projects file and reports. Includes correspondence with the Secretary of Human Affairs and members of the Virginia Council for the Deaf.
  - Secretary of Human Affairs, 1973. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Affairs, 1974 Jan-June. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Affairs, 1974 July-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Affairs, 1975. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1976. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1978 Jan-June. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1978 July-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1979 Jan-Sept. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1979 Oct-Dec. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1980 Jan-Mar. (Box 1)
  - Secretary of Human Resources, 1980 Apr-July. (Box 1)
  - Writing samples, 1988. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1973. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1974. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1975. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1976. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1978. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence, 1982. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Altizer, Reuben), 1975-1988. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Bellefleur, Phillip), 1978-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Cherry, Vernon), 1973-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Crockett, Claude), 1974-1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Cutler, S. James), 1980-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Shook, Wayne), 1980-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Smith, R. Sams), 1972-1973. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Smith, R. Sams), 1974-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Wallenborn, Dr. White), 1980-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Ziskind, David), 1973-1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Legislation, 1978. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Legislation, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - M, 1975-1982. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Masons, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1974-1978. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1975. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1976. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1978. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, Dept. of, 1982. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Miss Deaf Virginia Pageant, 1978-1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Model Secondary School for the Deaf, 1974-1983. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for the Deaf, 1974-1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for the Deaf, 1978. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for the Deaf, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for the Deaf, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for the Deaf, 1981-1982. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for the Deaf (Section 504, Rehabilitation Act), 1977-1983. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - National Association for Hearing and Speech Action, 1977-1978. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1978. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1979 Jan-Apr. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1979 May-July. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1979 Aug-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1980 Jan-May. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1980 June-Aug. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1980 Sept-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Articles, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Publications, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1981 Jan-May. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1981 Apr-July. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1981 Aug-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1982. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1983. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board), 1984-1986. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - McConnell, William, 1974-1979. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Moore, Leva, 1979-1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Morris, Robert, 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Myers, Patricia, 1979-1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Purvis, Rex, 1974-1975. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Board) - Shinpaugh, Joe, 1975-1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1977-1978. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1979. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1979. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1980 Feb-July. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1980 Aug-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1981 Jan-June. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (Secretary of Human Resources), 1981 July-Dec. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Administrative correspondence, 1978. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Administrative correspondence, 1979. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Administrative correspondence, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Administrative correspondence, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Advisory Council, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Bass, Aumen, 1978-1979. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Bass, Aumen, 1980-1981. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Budget, 1979-1980. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Center for the Def, 1975-1981. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (General), 1979-1982. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Correspondence (General), 1987. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Education, Dept. of, 1975-1976. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Indigent Health Care, 1987. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Interpreter Services, 1977-1980. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Interpreting, 1974-1977. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Issue, Needs and Concerns, 1978-1984. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Legislation Planning, 1981-1982. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of, 1978-1980. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Needs, 1983. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Overview, 1984. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Proposals for General Assembly, 1983. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Reorganization, 1977. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Town Hall meetings, 1980-1981. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1981 Jan-July. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1981 Aug-Dec. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1982. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983 Jan-July. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983 Aug-Dec. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1984. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1988. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990. (Box 5)
  - Budget (1982-1984 Biennium), 1981. (Box 5)
  - Dept. of Planning and Budget, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Dept. of Planning and Budget, 1982-1983. (Box 5)
  - Legislation, 1982-1983. (Box 5)
  - Legislation, 1983-1984. (Box 5)
  - Legislation - HB 977, 1976-1977. (Box 5)
  - Human Resources - Policy and timeframe for actions and responses, 1982. (Box 6)
  - Sample presentation on Virginia Council for the Deaf budget to the Human Resources Subcommittee of the House Appropriations Committee, 1981. (Box 6)
  - Critical issues - Human Resources, 1985. (Box 6)
  - State Agency Legislative Proposals (1984 Session), 1983. (Box 6)
  - Required signatures for expenditures, 1981. (Box 6)
  - State Councils/Commissions for the Deaf, 1982-1984. (Box 6)
  - Survey questionnaires on Deaf Councils/Commissions, n.d.. (Box 6)
  - Organization of state agencies for the deaf, 1982. (Box 6)
  - National Assocation of the Deaf - Convention, 1984. (Box 6)
  - Overal Advisory Council on Needs of Handicapped Persons, 1981-1982. (Box 6)
  - Report of the Task Force on Deafness (Mass.), 1985. (Box 6)
  - Reorganization of State Government, 1982. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981-1984. (Box 6)
  - Virginia Dept. for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing Forum, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Hearing aids, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Hearing aid telephone compatibility, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Hear Say, 1987. (Box 7)
  - HJR 276 Report, 1987. (Box 7)
  - HJR 276 Report, 1988. (Box 7)
  - Appreciative remarks about message relay service, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Important documents, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Agency head meetings, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Center for Independent Living, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Commission on Deaf Education, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Deaf senior citizens, undated. (Box 7)
  - Disability related legislation, 1987. (Box 7)
  - DRD - Plan of cooperation, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Educational interpreters, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Interpreter Services Program, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Interpreter Services Program - Quality Assurance Screeners, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Interpreter Services Program - Report of no shows, 1987. (Box 7)
  - I and R responses, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Interpreter policies, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Interpreter Services - Problems, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Interpreter Services - Advisory Committee, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Education issues, 1987. (Box 7)
  - National Association of the Deaf - Finance Committee, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Mental health issues, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Roundtable group, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Speaker of the House, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Tidewater Association for Hearing Impaired Children, 1987. (Box 7)
  - Target guidance, 1987-1990. (Box 7)
  - TDD Study, 1987. (Box 7)
  - TDD Study - Meeting, 1987 Aug. (Box 7)
  - Self help for hard of hearing people, 1987-1988. (Box 7)
  - Transitional Living Center, 1981-1987. (Box 7)
  - Legislation - HB 817, 1984. (Box 7)
  - Task Force - Missed Opportunities, 1984. (Box 7)
  - Dual Party Relay Service Task Force, 1989. (Box 7)
  - Human resources, 1985-1986. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990 Jan-July. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990 July-Dec. (Box 7)
  - Reports, 1990. (Box 7)
  - Aging, 1974-1976. (Box 9)
  - Aging, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Aging, 1978-1982. (Box 9)
  - Aging, undated. (Box 9)
  - American Instructors of the Deaf, 1978-1980. (Box 9)
  - Catholic Deaf of Richmond, 1976-1977. (Box 9)
  - Centrex RTTY, 1980-1981. (Box 9)
  - Children, Virginia Division for, 1973-1981. (Box 9)
  - Commission on State Governmental Management, 1975-1977. (Box 9)
  - Community colleges, 1975-1981. (Box 9)
  - Conference for Executives of American Schools for the Deaf, 1976-1980. (Box 9)
  - Cooperative project, 1974-1975. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1983. (Box 9)
  - Federal legislation, 1974-1977. (Box 9)
  - General, 1973-1983. (Box 9)
  - Governor's Employment Training, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Housing, 1974-1978. (Box 9)
  - Human resource priorities, 1975. (Box 9)
  - Identification and Diagnosis of Handicapped Children, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Industry Relations Committee workshop, 1975. (Box 9)
  - Interagency Project to Improve Services to the Deaf, 1976. (Box 9)
  - Interpreting workshop, 1979. (Box 9)
  - Learing Technology Institute, 1977. (Box 9)
  - Learnign Technology Institute, 1978-1979. (Box 9)
  - Legislation, 1977-1979. (Box 9)
  - Legislation, 1980-1981. (Box 9)
  - Lynchburg Training School and Hospital, 1977-1979. (Box 9)
  - Mayor's Committee on Employment of the Handicapped, 1975-1982. (Box 9)
  - Legislation, 1977-1979. (Box 8)
  - Legislation, 1980-1981. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Connecticut, 1975-1978. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Louisiana, 1975-1978. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Maryland, 1975-1978. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Massachusetts, 1978-1980. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Michigan, 1983. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Minnesota, 1975-1978. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Mississippi, 1976-1977. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Missouri, 1976-1977. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Nebraska, 1979-1981. (Box 8)
  - Other states - New Jersey, 1976-1984. (Box 8)
  - Other states - New York, 1975. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Oklahoma, 1975. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Oregon, 1975-1978. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Pennsylvania, 1979. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Rhode Island, 1976. (Box 8)
  - Other states - South Carolina, 1975-1977. (Box 8)
  - Other states - South Dakota, 1976. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Tennessee, 1979-1980. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Texas, 1974-1981. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Utah, 1978-1979. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Washington, 1980. (Box 8)
  - Other states - Wisconsin, 19. (Box 8)
  - Research Committee, 1977. (Box 8)
  - Research Committee, 1977-1986. (Box 8)
  - Residential placement guidelines, 1978-1979. (Box 8)
  - Richmond ARC, 1987-1988. (Box 8)
  - Richmond Career Education Center, 1980-1981. (Box 8)
  - Richmond Center for the Deaf - Advisory Committee, 1975-1981. (Box 8)
  - Roberts, Gary, 1978. (Box 8)
  - Roop, Lewis J., Sr., 1973-1983. (Box 8)
  - Ryan, Dennis, 1978-1981. (Box 8)
  - Southern Institute for Human Resources, 1980. (Box 8)
  - Telecommunications Council, 1980-1981. (Box 8)
  - Telecommunications devices for the deaf, 1981-1982. (Box 8)
  - Virginia Council for the Deaf - Organization, 1972-1980. (Box 8)
  - Welfare, Dept. of, 1977-1980. (Box 8)
  - Workshop and conference planning, 1978. (Box 8)
  - World Games, 1977. (Box 8)
  - Yates, Leo, 1978-1982. (Box 8)
- Director's correspondence and subject files (Accession 41647), 1974-2001., Extent: 5 cubic feet. (Box 1-5)
  This series is housed in 5 boxes and is arranged in original order. Records include correspondence, financial documentation, meeting files, projects file and reports. Includes VDDHH Advisory Board records, 1981-1991.
  - Executive agreements, 1982-1984. (Box 1)
  - Executive agreements, 1983. (Box 1)
  - Executive agreements, 1982-1986. (Box 1)
  - Executive agreements status reports, 1982-1983. (Box 1)
  - Executive agreements status reports, 1983-1984. (Box 1)
  - Executive agreements status reports, 1984-1985. (Box 1)
  - Executive agreements status reports, 1985-1986. (Box 1)
  - Survey, 1978-1979. (Box 1)
  - Planning District Registry, undated. (Box 1)
  - Financial proposal, 1986-1988. (Box 1)
  - Budget papers, 1979-1980. (Box 1)
  - Open House, 1990-1991. (Box 1)
  - Committee on Housing the Disabled, 1984-1985. (Box 1)
  - Program Proposal for Virginia Commission for the Deaf, 1982-1988. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Commission for the Deaf Workbook, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement, 1994. (Box 2)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement - HELPS Pilot and Letters from Lt. Gov. Beyer, 1994. (Box 2)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement - Pre-Pilot letters, 1994. (Box 2)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement - Pilot evaluation forms, 19. (Box 2)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement - HJR 2 Emergency law enforcement study, 1992. (Box 2)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement - Correspondence, 1993-1994. (Box 2)
  - Best Practices Guide for Police and Law Enforcement - Reports, 1993-1994. (Box 2)
  - A - General, 1976-1983. (Box 3)
  - A-95 Review, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Adelanski, Morton, 1977. (Box 3)
  - Advisory Committee on Deafness, 1975. (Box 3)
  - Advisory Committee on Deafness, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
  - Advisory Committee on Deafness, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
  - Aging, Virginia Office on, 1975-1979. (Box 3)
  - Auld Lang Syne Alumni Association of Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind, 1974-1983. (Box 3)
  - Arkansas Council for the Deaf, undated. (Box 3)
  - Arizona Council for the Deaf, 1978. (Box 3)
  - Attorney General, Office of the, 1975-1981. (Box 3)
  - Architectural and transportation barriers, 1980. (Box 3)
  - American Heart Association, 1978. (Box 3)
  - B - General, 1976-1983. (Box 3)
  - Balfour, Louis, 1980-1982. (Box 3)
  - Bass, R. Aumon, 1976-1978. (Box 3)
  - Bell, A.G. - Association for the Deaf, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
  - Blackwell, Warren C., 1975-1978. (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Alyce, 1978. (Box 3)
  - Centex, 1980-1982. (Box 3)
  - Christian, Evelyn, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
  - Clark, Blake, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Colorado, 1975-1977. (Box 3)
  - Council for the Deaf - North Carolina, 1979-1981. (Box 3)
  - California, 1978-1980. (Box 3)
  - Chandler (Kathy, Sam, Vicky), 1981. (Box 3)
  - CETA, 1979-1980. (Box 3)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1991 Sept. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1991 May. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1991 Feb. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1990 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1990 May. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1990 Nov. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1989 Sept. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1989 May. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1989 Feb. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1986 Nov. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1986 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1986 May. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1986 Feb. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1985 Nov. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1985 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1985 May. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1985 Feb. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1984 Oct. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1984 June. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1984 Mar. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1983 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1983 Sept. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1983 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1983 June. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1983 Mar. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1982 Dec. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1982 Sept. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1982 June. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meeting, 1982 Mar. (Box 4)
  - Advisory Board meetings, 1981. (Box 4)
  - National Day of Hearing Testing, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Virginia State Police - New trooper training, 1999-2000. (Box 5)
  - Virginia State Police - 911 Recertification, 1999-2001. (Box 5)
  - Basic TTY training information, 2000-2001. (Box 5)
  - ADA - Hotels and theaters, undated. (Box 5)
  - Assistive listening devices, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Assistive technology resources, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Audiology, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Computerized Assistive Notetaking (CAN), undated. (Box 5)
  - Real time captioning and Computer Assisted Real Time (CART), 1998. (Box 5)
  - Close captioning, 1999. (Box 5)
  - Cochlear implants, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Digital technology / Broadband, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Equipment distribution programs, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Hard of hearing information, 2000. (Box 5)
  - Hearing aids - Financial assistance, 1999. (Box 5)
  - Job Accomodation Network, 1997. (Box 5)